Guide to the Martin Gardner Papers SC0647
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Subject files, Series 2
  - Polycubes, 15 folder(s)
    - Soma Cubes [1 of 2], 1957-1997 (Box 54, Folder 21)
      Many articles and booklets on Soma Cube
      Correspondance about Parker Bros. publishing Soma, patents, etc
      Inquirees about patents, sales, etc
      Interview of Piet Hein
    - Soma Cubes [2 of 2], 1970-2000 (Box 54, Folder 22)
      Adlai game
      Much information, patents, pictures etc of various 3x3x3 cubes, from Jerry Slocum
    - Soma Figures [1 of 2], 1958-1974 (Box 55, Folder 1)
      Many fiigures to build, and proofs of impossibility of other figures
      Bound set of duplicate letters to MG (from GilOutterson)
      Correspondance between Outterson & Piet Hein about manufacturing Soma Cubes
      Much reader correspondance from 1958 S.A. column
      Lyons, Vossburgh (VOZ)
      Outterson, Gil
    - Soma Figures [2 of 2], 1976-1993 (Box 55, Folder 2)
      MG notes & original structures
      Nice, large-scale drawings of several figures
      Printouts of all solutions of the cube, raised cross, and crystal, from Sivy Farhi
      Farhi, Sivy
    - 3x3x3 Puzzles, 1972-1992 (Box 55, Folder 3)
      (Also see box 54, folder 22)
      Diabolical Cube - MG notes, analysis
      Lesk Cubes
      JPhilpott, Wade
      Dye, Daniel
    - Polycubes, Etc. [1 of 2], 1961-1990 (Box 55, Folder 4)
      Many MG notes, and others notes
      "Polycubes", from "More Mathematical Puzzles", chapter 6 (by G.J. Westerink?), typed & drawn
      Notes on Alan Schoen visit
      Class notes on Solving the Polycubes, by W.M. McKernan, 1973, 52pp (typescript)
      "Counting Multidimentional Polyominoes", by W.F. Lunnon, 1973, 8pp (typescript)
      Description of "Adlai" game
      McKeeman, William
      Bird, David
    - Polycubes, Etc. [2 of 2], 1959-1998 (Box 55, Folder 5)
      More polycube designs and puzzles
    - Impuzzables, 1972-1985 (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - Tetracubes, 1967-1992 (Box 55, Folder 7)
      "Wit's End", Putzl
      Notes on "Wit's End" puzzle, by Martin Scullin (many figures)
      "The First Book of Putzl", by L.E. Minnick (typescript)
    - Pentacubes, 1962-1993 (Box 55, Folder 8)
      Besley patent (3,065,970), 1962
      Trimetropentomino, richard, Serena & Beth Sutton
      Pentacube & hexacube tilings
    - The 12 "Solid" Pentominoes, 1958-1992 (Box 55, Folder 9)
      Several "Quint-Grams", from Kadon Enterprises (Nos 1-8, 12)
      Marketed version of the pentominoes
    - Hexacubes, 1964-1973 (Box 55, Folder 10)
      Baker, Jack
      Bouwkamp, C.J.
    - The Heptacubes, 1972 (Box 55, Folder 11)
    - Non-cube Polyhedra (Splatts), 1987 (Box 55, Folder 12)
      Splatt is a truncated octahedron
      1 article (from Eureka 47, by Mrk Owen & Mathew Richards)
    - The 5x5x5 "Dorian" & a "Logical Subset" of Pentacubes, 1972-1975 (Box 55, Folder 13)
      Dorie, Joseph
  - Polyhex
    - Polyhex [1 of 3], 1966-1984 (Box 56, Folder 1)
      Analysis of pentahex (by Paul Himebaugh)
      Hexahex ennumeration
      Many tetrahex solutions (from S.A. column), some by computer, and new patterns
    - Polyhex [2 of 3], 1962-1967 (Box 56, Folder 2)
      More solutions, analyses, and new patterns for polyhexes
      Klarners analysis
      Sharp, John
    - Polyhex [3 of 3], 1964-1984 (Box 56, Folder 3)
      More patterns and analysis
      Diagrams of many (all?) pentahex solutions of rhombus (by Paul Himebaugh)
      Klarner, Robert
  - Polyhexes, 3 folder(s)
    - Polyhex Ennumeration, 1967-1972 (Box 54, Folder 8)
      Several ennumerations, with some diagrams, of orders 4-12
      Gilbert, Walter
      Travnicek, Edward
    - Polyhex Tiling, 1967 (?) - 1995 (Box 54, Folder 9)
      A small number of problem solutions from Clarke, with proofs
      Clarke, Andrew
    - Triangular Lattice Problems, 1990 (Box 54, Folder 10)
      Several articles and typescripts of problems and solutions and proofs
      Hanegraaf, Anton
      West, Donald
  - Polyiamonds
    - Polyiamonds, undated (Box 54, Folder 7)
      No content; a couple of references
  - Polyobalos, Etc, 10 folder(s)
    - Polyabolo Tiling, undated (Box 54, Folder 11)
      (Right-andled triangle pieces)
      Also tetratans (tetrabolos), polyarcs
    - 3-D Polyaboloes, 1967 (Box 54, Folder 12)
      Theory in letter form Andrew Clarke
    - Polyaboloes, 1965-1974 (Box 54, Folder 13)
      Analysis from Tom O'Beirne, Wilfred Shepherd, James Taylor
      Shephard nomenclature (polytryngles, polyubes, etc)
      Set of cardboard tetraboloes [[ in 3-D box ]]
      Taggart, Mary
    - Polyabolo Ennumeration, 1967 (Box 54, Folder 14)
      Various counts by various people
    - Langford's 4-Piece Replication Problem, 1963 (Box 54, Folder 15)
    - The Tetrabolo Squares, Rectangles & Rhomboids, 1967-1977 (Box 54, Folder 16)
      Many results from John Harris, Philpott, Trigg
    - Rhombiominoes, 1993 (Box 54, Folder 17)
      1 article/problem, from J.R.M. by Kate Jones
    - Rookominoes, undated (Box 54, Folder 18)
      1 MG notes and reference
    - Paving Stones, 1994 (Box 54, Folder 19)
      1 reference
    - Misc. Variants, 2001 (Box 54, Folder 20)
      From Ed Pegg Jr's Mathpuzzle.com website
      References to CFF
      Eternity Puzzle
  - Polyominos, 25 folder(s)
    - General, 1957-2002 (Box 52, Folder 13)
      Problem: Tile 8x9 board with 11 1x6 bricks plus 1 2x3 rectangle
      "Polyomino and Polyiamond Problems", by Wade Philpott, 1976 (typescript)
      Description of MacPoly (from Sabaki Corp)
      "Polyominoes in a Random Tiling", by Michael Beeler, 1988 (typescript)
      "Modest Polyominoes", by Richard Hess, Y. Kotani, & Robert Wainwright (typescript)
      Bush, V.
      Lerner, David
    - Polyomino Computer Programs, 1958-1970 (Box 52, Folder 14)
      Lots of programs for various polyomino problems
    - Polyomino Enumeration Problem, 1958-1987 (Box 52, Folder 15)
      Many articles & letters, especially by Grank Harary
    - Dominos, 1965-1995 (Box 52, Folder 16)
      Several articles (mostly on covering rectangles with dominos)
    - Domino (Bricks) (Cards) Overhangs, 1964-1985 (Box 53, Folder 1)
      Several articles & letters
    - Trominoes, 1971-1998 (Box 53, Folder 2)
      Articles, letters, notes on problems involving trominoes
    - Tetrominoes, 1960-1998 (Box 53, Folder 3)
      Several tetromino problems, in notes and letters and some articles
    - Pentomino & Higher Tiling Problems [1 of 2], 1954-1984 (Box 53, Folder 4)
      "There is no Gap in a Diamond", by Mogens Esrom Larsen, 1986 (pamphlet)
      Lots of Leigh Mercer correspondance
      Many problems & solutions, in various articles & letters
      Garcia, Abel
    - Pentomino & Higher Tiling Problems [2 of 2], 1960-2000 (Box 53, Folder 5)
      Many more problems, solutions, counts of numbers of solutions, etc
      The 5 superposition problems
      "A Pedestrian Approach to a Method of Conway, or, A Tile of Two Cities", by James Propp, 1993 (typescript)
      Digby, David
    - Pentomino "Farms", 1972-1990 (Box 53, Folder 6)
      Feser, Victor
      Kotani, Yoichi
    - Pentominoes (Misc), 1960-1998 (Box 53, Folder 7)
      Many more puzzles & problems
      Pentomino patents & trademark information and court case
      MacPoly, short description (David Lerner, Sabaki Corp.)
      Covering cubes with pentominoes
      2339 solutions to 6x10 pentomino tiling, by Bethel Hooven
      Inflated pentominoes
      FILL-AGREE - A punctured polyomino puzzles by Kate Jones*
      Modest Polyominoes Problems Book and Modest Hexominoes Puzzle, by Dick Hess*
      [[ items marked "*" are in 3-D box ]]
      Hooven, Bethel
      Kurchan, Rodulfo
    - Pentomino 13-Hole Problem (& Other Hole Problems), 1969-1973 (Box 53, Folder 8)
      Bouwkamp, C.W.
      Lindstedt, Christer
    - Sawtooth Square Patterns, 1960-1964 (Box 53, Folder 9)
      Solutions with empty square in a corner (or adjacent), and several proofs the hole cnnot gbe in the middle
    - Scott Taylor Pattern, 1960-1963 (Box 53, Folder 10)
      Several proofs of impossibility
    - Golomb's Pentomino Game, 1963-1973 (Box 53, Folder 11)
      Rules (by Golomb) of his Pentomino Game
      Description of program, by S. Kurzba m & T. McBride to play pentomino game
      Correspondance about rights to pentomino game
      McBride, Tom
    - Polyomino Games, 1960-1978 (Box 53, Folder 12)
      Pan-Kai
      Kent Wadsworth game, one-sided pentomino pieces with values
      Cogito (French)
      Zim
      Skirrid
      Locus
      Copade (Kenneth Costa)
    - Hexominoes, 1962-1999 (Box 53, Folder 13)
      1-sided vs 2-sided discussion
      Dr. Hex
      Spear's Multipuzzle
      Complete set of pents & hexes, plastic, solved as a red 15x18 rectangle of hexominoes, with a contiguous green "Chess rook" of pentominoes in the center [[ in 3-D folder ]]
      (D. Woods letter also contains "superparadoxes" and a chessboard problem)
      Sherman, Henry
    - Heptominoes (Order 7), 1955-1995 (Box 53, Folder 14)
      Lists of the pieces, and some problems & solutions
    - 8-Ominoes & Higher, 1972-1988 (Box 53, Folder 15)
      Monomino density
      Interlocking polyominoes
      Serial Isogons
      Pi-sided polyominoes
    - Corner-Connected Squares (Think-A-Ma-Jig), 1973 (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - Rhominoes, 1976-1992 (Box 54, Folder 2)
      James Parker: analysis of 60 degree rhombuses (but tri-rhombuses are a subset of hexiamonds)
      Parker, James
    - Bicolored Polyominoes, 1983-1995 (Box 54, Folder 3)
      Some checkerboard colorings & problems
      Quintachex
    - Polycycles (Dutch), 1979 (Box 54, Folder 4)
      Notes from Luitzen Yntena on polyomino variations
    - Bibliography for Solomon Golomb, 1988-1991 (Box 54, Folder 5)
      Polyomino references to about 1991, compiled by MG for Golomb:
      Books by Martin Gardner
      Polyomino references (from 1988)
      New references added in 1991
      Chessboard dissections into polyominoes
      Books
      Tiling
      Marketed polyomino games
      On rectification, on polyiamonds, on tetraboloes, on polyhexes, on polycubes, etc
      J. of Rec. Math references
    - Polyomino Tiling of Plane, 1995 (Box 54, Folder 6)
      "Tiling Rectangles with Polyominoes", by Solomon Golomb (typescript)
  - Primes, 26 folder(s)
    - Goldbach Conjecture, 1978-1987 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Sklansky, David
    - Rieman Hypothesis (Zeta Function), 1972-2002 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Poem: "Where are the zeros of zeta of s?"
    - Mersenne Primes, 1978-2001 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Lee, L.E.J.
      Eberhart, Stephen
    - General References, 1953-1997 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Also articles on basic prime info: sieves, prime number theorem, unique factorization, etc.
      Wade, Carlton
      McDonnell, E.E.
    - Primes (Misc.-Curios-Problem, etc) [ 1 of 3], 1961-1981 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      "The Numerology of One Hundred", by Solomon Golomb (mimeograph)
      Overlapping 9-digit primes
      "Prime Period Length Counts and Ratios", by Samuel Yates (typescript)
      "A Phsicist's Proof of Fermat's Theorem of Primes", by H. Gutfreund & W.A. Little (typescript)
      Long essay on "Alpha Operation", by Howard Bergerson, 1981 (typescript)
    - Primes (Misc.-Curios-Problem, etc) [ 2 of 3], 1964-1987 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      "A Class of Primality Tests for Trinomials Which Includes the Lucas-Lehmer Test", by H.C. Williams (typescript)
      Williams, Hugh
      Adams, Milton
    - Primes (Misc.-Curios-Problem, etc) [ 3 of 3], 1975-2000 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      "Strong Law of Small Numbers", by Richard Guy (photocopy of manuscript)
      Lots of articles, and MG notes
    - Twin Primes (& Variants), 1964-2001 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      "Prime-Number Pairs", by Schuyler M. Christian, 1985 (booklet)
      "Titanic Twins", by Samuel Yates (typescript)
      "On Prime Densities and Twin Prime Fallacies", by F.E. von Ammon Jr
      "Proof of the Infinitude of Double Twin Primes", by Martin Aaronson
      "A Relation Between Twin Primes and their Indices", by A.R. Fazely
      Christian, Schuyler
      Crandall, R.E.
      Aaronson, Martin
    - Fermat Numbers & Primes, 1990-1996 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      "A Tail of Two Sieves", by Carl Pomerance
    - Tables (Decimal, Binary), 1993 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Sieves, Tests, Factoring, 1960-1998 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      "Primes, a Strictly Emperical Study", by F.B. von Amon, Jr (booklet)
      "Conway's Prime Producing Machine", by Richard Guy (typescript, ND)
      Ammon, F.E. von
      Dow, John
      Morse, Arthur
      Stilgebauer, Robert
      Meyer, Marvin
      Glass, John
      Litvack, Barry
      Pritchard, P.A.
    - Probability Tests of Primes, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      "A Note on Monte Carlo Primality Tests and Algorithmic Information Theory", by Gregory Chaitin & Jacob Schwartz (typescript draft)
      "Monte-Carlo Tests for Primality", by Donald Malm (typescript)
      "Probabilistic Algorithms", by Michael Rabin (typescript)
      "Riemann's Hypothesis and Tests for Primality", by Gary Miller (typescript)
      "A Fast Monte-Carlo Test for Primality", by R. Solovay & V. Strassen (reprint)
      Malm, Donald
    - 100-Digit Primes, 1964-1996 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      Mauchly, John
    - Repunit Primes (& 100-Digit Primes) [1 of 2], 1964-1985 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      Much from column March, 1964
      Schaechter, David
      Jordan, Steven
      Brillhart, John
      Chiles, Griffin
      Cohen, Martin
    - Repunit Primes (& 100-Digit Primes) [2 of 2], 1976-1985 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      "Divisibility with Repunit Factores", by Samuel Yates (typescript)
      Many letters & articles of Samuel Yates
    - Reversible Primes (Emirps), 1964-1999 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      Barbour, David
    - Palindromic Primes, Squares, Cubes, etc., 1969-1999 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Gustavus Simmons Factoring, & Lenstra, 1984-1986 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Prime Generating Formulas, 1964-1998 (Box 2, Folder 7)
      Szulyovszky, D.
      Koch, George
      Higgins, Olga
      Von Ammon, Fred
      Atkin, Oliver
    - Primes: Permutable, Snowballs, & Cyclics, Truncatable, etc., 1965-1997 (Box 2, Folder 8)
      Green, Milton
    - Mills Formula & Others Like It, 1963-1997 (Box 2, Folder 9)
      Cina, Jerome
    - Consecutive Digit Primes, 1972-1978 (Box 2, Folder 10)
      Cassel, Alan
    - Gaps of No Primes, 1964-1966 (Box 2, Folder 11)
      Brenner, Joel
    - Conjectures - False and Unproved, 1963-1985 (Box 2, Folder 12)
      Stevens, J.W.
    - Pseudo Primes (Ulam's Luck) (Poulet No's), undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Recent Tests for Primes, 1981-1986 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Primes in A.P. & Prime Squares, 5 folder(s)
    - Primes in Arithmetical Progressions, 1975-1995 (Box 2, Folder 15)
      Rose, Nicholas
      Fry, James
    - Prime Squares, ca.1913-1991 (Box 2, Folder 16)
      2 articles from "The Monist:
      "Magic Squares Made With Prime Numbers", by W.S. Andrews & Harry Sayles, 1913 (photocopy from The Monist)
      "Pandiagonal Prime Number Magic Squares", by Chas. D. Shuldham, 1914 (photocopy from The Monist)
      Walker, George
      Fendall, Chuck
    - Allan W. Johnson, Jr., 1981-1989 (Box 2, Folder 17)
      Johnson, Allan
    - Capt. Wm. H. Benson, 1927-1980 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      Various writings on prime magic squares, by Benson
    - Gukuho Abe, 1986-1988 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      Several articles in Japanese
      Abe, Gakuho
  - Probability, 34 folder(s)
    - Probability, 1950-2001 (Box 28, Folder 9)
      Many popu8lar science articles, some on "philosophy" of probability.
    - The 2 Shells & Switch of Choice [1 of 2], 1959-1992 (Box 28, Folder 10)
      3-door problem, 3 prisoners problem, Mondy Hall problem
      Many letters and much analysis of the problem (in various guises) and variations.
      Rosa, Domenico
      Frazier, Kendrick
    - undated (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - Vos Savant - Other Puzzles, 1991-2000 (Box 29, Folder 1)
      Lots of correspondance about problems from her column.
    - Probability Paradoxes (& Sucker Bets), 1968-1997 (Box 29, Folder 2)
      Many paradoxes, and many sucker bets
      "The Strange Game of Lucky Louie", by Michael Stueben (typescript)
      Winkless, Nelson Brock
    - Eldest Sono Paradox, 1972-1999 (Box 29, Folder 3)
      Two thirds of men are eldest sons.
    - Paradox of 2nd Ace, 1957-1992 (Box 29, Folder 4)
      Set of correspondance with Warren Weaver & Norman Gridgeman, with much discussion and analysis of the problem (1963-1964)
      Set of correspondance with John Ford
      Fuhrmann, Steve
    - Paradox of the Second Child, 1958-1992 (Box 29, Folder 5)
      Duggleby, R.G.
    - Birthday Paradox (& Variants), 1970-2001 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Necktie Paradox & Variants (May 77), 1975-2001 (Box 29, Folder 7)
      Exchanging envelopes with $x & $2x paradox
      Coffman, Bill
      Lewis, Hal
      Girard, Martin
    - Unfaithful Wives, 1985 (Box 29, Folder 8)
      2 reports on cheating husbands problem (same as unfaithful wives.)
      Halpern, Joe
    - Statistical Paradoxes, 1959-1999 (Box 29, Folder 9)
      Waiting time paradox
      Boltzmann's dice paradox
      Popular and technical aarticlas
    - Defining "Random" [1 of 2], 1952-1987 (Box 29, Folder 10)
      Several long papers
      Alcock, James
    - Defining "Random" [2 of 2], 1988-1992 (Box 29, Folder 11)
      Compagner, Aaldert
    - Probability & Cards (ESP also) [1 of 2], 1961-1978 (Box 30, Folder 1)
      Game with deck of 20 cards, by Howard (?)
      Several articles on chance
      Three-dimensional draw poker
      Several items from Persi Diaconis (notes by MG)
      Wilson, Robert Ross
    - Probability & Cards (ESP also) [2 of 2], 1967-1997 (Box 30, Folder 2)
      "The Analysis of Sequential Experiments with Feedback to Subjects", by Persi Diaconis & Ronald Graham, Tech. Rep. No. 119, 1978
    - Dice-Probability Problems, 1960-2002 (Box 30, Folder 3)
      Moser's problem (& Related ones) of loaded dice
      "Stochastic Inequalities", by Walter Funkenbusch, 1989 (typescript)
    - "Small World" Paradox, 1967-2000 (Box 30, Folder 4)
      Kochen, Manfred
    - First Digits in Tables - Benford's Law, 1960-1999 (Box 30, Folder 5)
      "Limits of Measures of the Integers With Application to Random Number Generators ...", by Persi Diaconis, 1973, Memorandum NS-211 (typescript)
      "On the Distribution of First Significant Digits", by Roger Pinkham, 1960 (dittograph)
      Duquet, Robert
      Federighi, Francis
    - "Random" Triangles, 1968-1982 (Box 30, Folder 6)
      Breaking a stick in 3 pieces - is it a triangle?
      Is a random triangle acute?
    - Matching Pennies Machines (Dunning), 1954-1975 (Box 30, Folder 7)
      Sprace (a Piet Hein gmae)
      Cleo (Computer to Learn Even-Odd), Dunning's machine
      SEER, A Sequence Extrapolating Robot - Hagelbargers machine
      Dunning, Charles
    - Simpson's Paradoxes & Other "Worst-Best", 1960-1992 (Box 30, Folder 8)
      March, 1976 column
      Many letters & articles
      "A Paradox", by J.W. Moon, 1975 (typescript)
      Moon, J.W.
    - On Poker, 1978-1981 (Box 30, Folder 9)
      "Is My Poker Hand Better Than Yours?", by William H. Cutler (typescript)
      "How To Cheat at Mental Poker", by Richard Lipton, 1979 (typescript)
    - Blackjack Systems, 1961-1979 (Box 30, Folder 10)
      Mostly newspaper articles
    - Monte Carlo Method, 1955-1958 (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - "Death-Dips" - Do Deaths Correlate with Important Events?, 1980 (Box 30, Folder 12)
      Is there a dip in the number of deaths before important events (birthdays, etc), or a rise after?
    - Negative Probability (Feynman), 1977 (Box 30, Folder 13)
      "Negative Probilities", by R.P. Feynman
      A paper on the concept of negative probabilities (by Feynman), with notes on it and a letter by MG.
      Feynman, Richard
    - Resampling (Efron's Bootstrap), 1984-1995 (Box 31, Folder 1)
      Several papers about Resampling & Bootstrap, by and about Simon & Efron
      Simon, Julian
    - Metaanalysis, 1992 (Box 31, Folder 2)
      Single article (by Ingram Olkin), from The Sciences
    - Transparent Proofs, 1992 (Box 31, Folder 3)
      2 short articles, from Focus and from Science
    - Probability Problems [1 of 2], 1957-1987 (Box 31, Folder 4)
      Many problems and puzzles
      "Two Statistical Fables", by Richard Zeckhauser, Discussion Paper No. 57, 1968 (typescript) I: "Decisions of Alice"; II: "A Tale of Probable Regions"
      Gardner's Dice
      Morgenstern, Leonard
      Dunne, Alex
      Upton, L.J.
      Moore, A.D.
      Griggs, Jerry
      Lenning, Alvar
      Gilbert, Edward
    - Probability Problems [2 of 2], 1968-1998 (Box 31, Folder 5)
      Many problems
      Physics of models for generating random events (in Diaconis letter)
      Potvin, robert
    - Roulette, 1993-1999 (Box 31, Folder 6)
      Single paper: "A Solution to Roulette", by Stephen Hu, 1993 (typescript)
    - Doomsday Argument, 2000 (Box 31, Folder 7)
      MG note
      computer printout of article (a literature review)
  - Sequences, 16 folder(s)
    - Integer Sequences, 1965-2001 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      MG notes on 2 R. Penrose problems.
      "Find the Next Term", by Neil Sloane (typescript) - sequence puzzles
      "Computer-Aided Analysis of Monotonic Sequence Games", by Frank Harary, Bruce Sagan, David West (typescript)
      Van Tooren, A.
      Sagan, Bruce
    - Looping Problems "Black Holes", 1945-2000 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Looping Problem - 3X+1 [1 of 2], 1978-1982 (Box 6, Folder 3)
      (Collatz conjecture, Syracuse problem, Hailstone numbers)
      Wilber, james
    - Looping Problem - 3X+1 [2 of 2], 1971-1999 (Box 6, Folder 4)
      Christy, Donald
    - Palindrome Conjecture, 1961-1996 (Box 6, Folder 5)
      "A Note on Palindromes by Addition", by Michael Rebmann & Frank Sentyrz (typescript)
      "A Study of Palindromic Numbers", by D.R. Kaprekar, 1976
      "Researches on Reversed Subtraction Process", by D.R. Kaprekar, 1977
      Beatty, Millard
    - Fibonacci, 1961-2000 (Box 6, Folder 6)
      Lots of short articles.
      Feinberg, Andrew
    - Applications, 1951-1977 (Box 6, Folder 7)
      "Life, Form, and Number", by C.A.B. Smith, 1965 (pamphlet)
    - Fib. Magic Tricks, 1959-1978 (Box 6, Folder 8)
      Heath's Fibonacci Trick, AAG Principle, Fibonacci Fantasy
    - Fib. Variants, 1968-1999 (Box 6, Folder 9)
      A Tribanacci Application
      Vibronacci numbers
      Webb, Edward
    - Proberties, Curiosities, etc., 1964-1992 (Box 6, Folder 10)
      Albright, Charles
    - Harmonic Series, 1963-1997 (Box 6, Folder 11)
      "Partial Sums of the Harmonic Series", by R.B. Boas & John Wrench (typescript)
      "Optimal Card Stacking", by Brad Jackson (typescript)
      Engel, Joseph
    - Thue Sequence & Infinite Chess (Non-repeating Chains), 1957-1998 (Box 6, Folder 12)
      Beek, Allan
    - Linus (& Sally) Sequences, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 13)
      Notes from Scott Kim
      Hellerstein, Nathaniel
    - Conways, 1, 2, 3, 1984-1997 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Golomb's Self-Ref. Sequence, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 15)
      2 articles and short note.
    - Farey Sequences, 1967-1995 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Serial Isogons
    - Isogon Paper, 1988-1996 (Box 14, Folder 1)
      "Contour Codes of Isothetic Polygons", by Prabir Bhattacharya & Azriel Rosenfeld, Aug. 1988 (U. Md. Report)
      Alexanderson, G.L.
  - Software Projects, 11 folder(s)
    - Programmed Card Tricks, 1966-1996 (Box 47, Folder 1)
      Clock-Card Trick, Hans Trixer
      "Magical Mathematics", by Persi Diaconis & Ron Graham (typescript) - outline of book to teach mathematical appreciation with magic tricks
      "Powerful Magic", by Michael Powers (104 pp) (1983) (booklet)